# Makiko Vaughan

(404) 374-6059 | makiko.vaughan@gmail.com | Sharpsburg, Georgia

https://www.linkedin.com/in/makiko-vaughan | https://makikovaughan.github.io/myPortfolio/

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Detail-oriented problem solver with 460+ training hours and experience developing full stack Java applications. Interested in attaining a career that will allow me the opportunity to excel in software development as well as highlight my previous work experience and leadership abilities.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

# W3Schools JavaScript Certification (Passed in November, 2022)

- Java
- JavaScript (LinkedIn Badge)
- HTML (LinkedIn Badge)
- CSS
- Spring Boot
- React

- Spring Data JPA
- Spring Security (JWT)
- Bootstrap
- REST API's
- SQL
- Unit Testing (JUnit, Mockito)
- Node
- SOLID OOP Principles
- Dependencies Injection
- Git

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Cook Systems | Remote | January 2023 - March 2023

FastTrack Developer

- Received an 8 week, 320+ hour training by creating the Frontend page to send and receive request using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Axios, and React with multiple packages
- Developed and created a database schema from scratch to support Postgres DB in PGAdmin
- Applied Spring Boot and JPA to manipulate HTTP request and business logics with controllers, services, and accessed database with repositories

## **Generation Junior Full Stack Java Developer Program** | Remote | August 2022- December 2022 *Training Participant*

- Participated in a 16-week, 460+ hour Junior Full Stack Java Developer program that emphasizes hands-on practical application
- Learned and deploying the technologies involved in creating full stack web applications with Java using Spring Boot Framework, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3
- Implemented basic unit tests

# **TSG USA, Inc.** | Peachtree City, Georgia | July 2017 – August 2018 & June 2019 – June 2022 System Testing Engineer

- Created and conducted 100+ test cases for Panasonic Car Audio System (Honda, Toyota, and Mazda)
- Identified possible defects and its source by reading Audio Specification, then reported findings to development team
- Conducted effectiveness confirmation tests once defects were fixed

### Georgia Tech Coding Bootcamp | Atlanta, Georgia | September 2018 – December 2018

Training Participant

- Participated in a 12-week, 240+ hour Full Stack Flex Web Development that emphasizes hands-on class room sessions
- Learned the technologies involved in front-end and back-end (MongoDB, MySQL, Node.is, express.is)
- Received "The Most Likely to Startup" and "The Best in Class" for the last group project by the last Group project

### **EDUCATION**

### Keller Graduate School of Management of DeVry University

- Master of Information Systems Management
- Cumulative GPA: 3.80/4.00
- Graduated with Distinction